<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Pages on Hugi's Elephant</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Hugi's Elephant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugiselephant.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ChatGPT is getting crazy</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/chatgpt-is-getting-crazy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/chatgpt-is-getting-crazy/</guid><description>Trying to learn what I can do with ChatGPT and found this. Seems like imagination is the only limiting factor now.
{{tweet https://twitter.com/skirano/status/1635736107949195278?s=20}}
So I tried it too. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have to do the first set up prompt. All I asked was one line.
generate code for a pong like game in javascript and HTML
pong.html</description></item><item><title>Joy without Guilt</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/joy-without-guilt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/joy-without-guilt/</guid><description>I am very grateful, and I feel very fortunate. I just came back from a one week trip to Los Cabos Mexico.
Feeling Joy Escaping the grey weather.
Being in such a beautiful exotic surrounding with palm trees, clear blue sky, and wales playing in the deep blue of the ocean.
Meeting people, experiencing different cultures.
Nurturing body and mind with time to pause, delicious food and sweet drinks.</description></item><item><title>I am grateful</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/i-am-grateful/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/i-am-grateful/</guid><description>I am grateful.</description></item><item><title>Northern lights road trip plan</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/northern-lights-road-trip-plan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/northern-lights-road-trip-plan/</guid><description>One dream scenario that I want to make reality in the next several years is to go on a North America road trip with my wife in an electric camper truck. We can experience a few months of van truck life, but without burning gas, or worrying about finding a place to stay each night. I think with the right gear it can be a very simple yet comfortable trip. I have many places I would love to visit and experience.</description></item><item><title>A magical Wallet that steals money from everyone in the world</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/a-magical-wallet-that-steals-money-from-everyone-in-the-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/a-magical-wallet-that-steals-money-from-everyone-in-the-world/</guid><description>When I was young I wished that I had a magical wallet that had one paper bill inside.
What good is a wallet with only one bill inside? You might ask&amp;hellip; Well, it was a magical wallet. I would be able to take the bill out and use it. Then magically another one appeared inside this magical wallet. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be nice? It is like the goose that lays unlimited golden eggs, or the fountain that never dries.</description></item><item><title>Sending a message to the future</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/sending-a-message-to-the-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/sending-a-message-to-the-future/</guid><description>I just got a message from the past. &amp;ldquo;Allergy attack 2010&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a message from my past self who is living in 2010 suffering painfully from a bad seasonal allergy attack.
Finally, after struggling year after year from seasonal allergies, my past self, one day in 2010 realized he needs to do something about it. He sent a message to me today in the future in 2023.
I hope you never experience seasonal allergies, or any other allergies for that matter, it really sucks.</description></item><item><title>The Santa Paradox</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/the-santa-paradox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/the-santa-paradox/</guid><description>I was thinking about consciousness. Then I had a moment of profound realization. You know the moment you go from not knowing to knowing something. Our brain probably evolved to reward these moments since it feels so good when this happens. This must be the motivation for all the curious minds. Joy of learning I suppose.
Suddenly all the things other wise people said started to make sense like puzzle pieces falling into place.</description></item><item><title>What if you don't know what your goals and desires are?</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-you-dont-know-what-your-goals-and-desires-are/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-you-dont-know-what-your-goals-and-desires-are/</guid><description>We are constantly told that we should be true to ourselves and pursue our deepest desires, but what if you don’t know what your goals and desires are? What if you have no idea what your “life purpose” is or should be? Self-direction is impossible without self-knowledge. How can you know what you want if you don’t know who you are? — from Building a Second Brain Book
I feel like this is the story of my life!</description></item><item><title>Publish using Logseq and Hugo</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/publish-using-logseq-and-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/publish-using-logseq-and-hugo/</guid><description>Outline
Image of process
Idea, planting the seed, incubating seedlings, feeding growing, Harvesting, Sharing Intro
What is a thought? Thinking about thinking so called Metathinking is one of the most interesting questions or it could be a great way to get your brain stuck in an infinite Recursion.
Ideas grow in a Nonlinear Workflow
in a safe an private place, second brain, architecs and the gardeners Logseq the safe incubating ideas Page</description></item><item><title>GoHugo.io</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/gohugo.io/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/gohugo.io/</guid><description>https://gohugo.io/ Open Source static site generator</description></item></channel></rss>