<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Pages on Hugi's Elephant</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Hugi's Elephant</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugiselephant.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two types of people</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/two-types-of-people/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/two-types-of-people/</guid><description>We can divide people into two groups people who want change, people who are ok with how it is.
People who are ok with how things are don&amp;rsquo;t do much and that&amp;rsquo;s ok.
People who want change do things. Things that are good many other things that are bad. We tend to judge lazy people but the bigger problems come from industrious people who do things that end up being a net negative.</description></item><item><title>Doing the same thing</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/doing-the-same-thing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/doing-the-same-thing/</guid><description>“Insanity is doing the same thing over and over and expecting different results.” — [[Albert Einstein]]</description></item><item><title>What if I've never tasted wine?</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-ive-never-tasted-wine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-ive-never-tasted-wine/</guid><description>Thinking about the impressive capabilities of LLM these days, I thought of some other takes on the [[Turing test]], or the [[Chinese room]] idea.
What if I&amp;rsquo;ve never tasted wine before but I can fake it.
A blind person describing the color red.
A con artist who pretends to love you.
If a car can drive as good as a human, then does it have awareness of the road like the human driver?</description></item><item><title>Looking at myself in the future</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/looking-at-myself-in-the-future/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/looking-at-myself-in-the-future/</guid><description>I saw an old couple getting out of the car. The old lady was having a hard time walking and was holding the man&amp;rsquo;s elbow. There was something there, that must have reminded me of my wife holding my arm. I suddenly had tear&amp;rsquo;s in my eyes&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know why. Maybe I feel like I am seeing a glimpse of me and my wife in the future.</description></item><item><title>Growing AI</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/growing-ai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/growing-ai/</guid><description>x.AI mission is to inderstand the universe. As Elon Musk puts it &amp;ldquo;What the hell is going on&amp;rdquo;. He talks about &amp;ldquo;Growing AI&amp;rdquo;. Giving two goals. Curiosity and Truth.
Children never do what their parents tell then to do. Good parenting will result in good children. Good children will take care of their parents&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Last day in Korea</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/last-day-in-korea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/last-day-in-korea/</guid><description>Today is my last day in Korea. Going to meet my friend. Uploading this post from the subway!</description></item><item><title>Speed of Korea</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/speed-of-korea/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/speed-of-korea/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 5 years since my last visit to Korea. And like many people who live abroad, because I only get to see Korea once in a while, I tend to notice the changes. Korea definitely is a place that has a lot of new things to notice. There is always something new and different. After Gangnam Style, BTS, Parasite, and of course Covid&amp;hellip; This time things felt a lot more different.</description></item><item><title>Logseq version 9.10 Smart Merge feature</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/logseq-version-9.10-smart-merge-feature/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/logseq-version-9.10-smart-merge-feature/</guid><description>Logseq today just (4 hours ago) released Version 9.10 So why am I so excited about this release that I am writing about it?
It is because of one feature that I have been waiting for for so long&amp;hellip; Smart Merge.
Logseq checked all the boxes for me It is my main note taking app, my [[PKM]], and my [[second brain]].
There are so many more great things about Logseq, but when it comes down to the deal breakers these were high on my list and believe me I have tried many apps and I can&amp;rsquo;t think of any that can do all of these things as well as Logseq.</description></item><item><title>What would The Last (insert product here) you ever need to buy look like?</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-would-the-last-insert-product-here-you-ever-need-to-buy-look-like/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-would-the-last-insert-product-here-you-ever-need-to-buy-look-like/</guid><description>Image generated by [[DiffusionBee app]] using the prompt &amp;ldquo;What would the last cup you ever need to buy look like?&amp;rdquo;
In the world where consumerism, fast fashion, instant, single use, and [[designed obsolescence]] is the most profitable business practice. What would the last product you need to buy look like?
The Last cup
The Last shoe
The Last bag
The Last jacket
The Last car
The Last house?
As a designer I am sad to think that design is causing more waste.</description></item><item><title>Going on a trip to Korea tomorrow</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/going-on-a-trip-to-korea-tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/going-on-a-trip-to-korea-tomorrow/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to Korea tomorrow and I am still not packed&amp;hellip; So I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to post anything longer.
Maybe I can share my packing checklist. Strangely enough, this is one of my most used templates! Compiled over time from my past mistakes. Every time I leave something behind and think, &amp;ldquo;I wish I had brought this on my trip&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I put it in this list. Very useful for me on every trip.</description></item><item><title>Spacial Computing</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/spacial-computing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/spacial-computing/</guid><description>Are you the master of your own reality? Or are you a slave of your temptation?
It used to be a philosophical question, but now it has become a more practical, technology question. Apple just announced the [[Vision Pro]]. And of course, everyone is jumping on the opportunity to give their two cents about Apple’s first stab at this new way of computing. It&amp;rsquo;s very noisy on the internet, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s exciting times again.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Truck Roadtrip Plan</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/cyber-truck-roadtrip-plan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/cyber-truck-roadtrip-plan/</guid><description>To make this a reality, a plan needs to be in place.
First I need to be able to imagine it! Then I will be able to make it real.
Ideas Brain Storming
Places, Cities, Landmarks, Natural marvels,
Activities, Paragliding, Scuba Diving,
Cultural Events, Festivals,
Natural Events, Celestial events,
People to meet
Family, Friends,
Making connections
Things I want to do
Total Solar eclipse in [[2024-04-08 Monday]] 8:42 AM
Learn and go Paragliding from popular flying spots</description></item><item><title>Wandering</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/wandering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/wandering/</guid><description>Where am I? Where am I going? Where do I want to be?
I just turned 49 and I still don&amp;rsquo;t have a clear answer to these questions&amp;hellip; Now I just accepted that my life is about wandering.
I think J.R.R Tolkien and Adel both once said
&amp;ldquo;Not all those who wander are lost.&amp;rdquo;
Once I realized that is what I am good at, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel so bad. The book 📖 Delivered From Distraction described brains like mine as &amp;ldquo;Chronic wandering of the mind&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Why do I need a thinking tool?</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/why-do-i-need-a-thinking-tool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/why-do-i-need-a-thinking-tool/</guid><description>“A Bicycle for the mind”. That’s what Steve Jobs called the computer back in the 90’s, because it was a tool that made our limited human mind more efficient. Now imagine, driving past the old bicycle on a new “self-driving car for your mind”. I think it’s time we get a little upgrade.
Let’s think about thinking, just bear with me for a minute&amp;hellip;
We all have a lot of “knowledge work” to do these days.</description></item><item><title>Higher and higher real estate price</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/higher-and-higher-real-estate-price/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/higher-and-higher-real-estate-price/</guid><description>When the price of homes you live in goes up, should you be happy that you are richer? Who is really benefiting from the higher price of homes?
Maybe you are one of the lucky people who bought low and sold high.
Maybe you got into the real estate game before a lot of other people and have a lot of properties that are making profit for you. You are the &amp;ldquo;Land Lord&amp;rdquo; why do we still call these people Lord anyways?</description></item><item><title>Sick</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/sick/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/sick/</guid><description>Being sick sucks.
There is nothing like feeling sick that drains any little motivation that I have left inside.
Physically painful, no energy, no will
Negative thought spiral
Just overall making me feel bad about everything.
I really am grateful for being generally healthy&amp;hellip;
My habit is barely propping me up. But it is working.
The reason I am even writing this is because I have a system that I set up using Complice.</description></item><item><title>What if AI makes money</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-ai-makes-money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-ai-makes-money/</guid><description>There has been no lack of AI anxiety going around. So let me just throw another idea out there.
What if AI makes money?
Of course it will be programmed to make money on its own.
Of course it is already better at a lot of things than most people.
Of course it will be better at doing everything even making money very soon.
AutoGPT already demonstrated that when given a goal an AI program can figure out how to achieve that goal.</description></item><item><title>They say AI is going to take my job. Don't worry.</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/they-say-ai-is-going-to-take-my-job.-dont-worry./</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/they-say-ai-is-going-to-take-my-job.-dont-worry./</guid><description>Looking around at the the crazy pace of AI development right now, it is getting more and more impossible to focus on anything these days. So much is swirling around us so fast no human can possibly keep up. It will only get exponentially faster I suppose.
Welcome to the singularity. What I see happening very soon, which is exciting to investors and businesses but scary and sad for workers is that everyone will start working on a last project that will train the AI to replace their own job.</description></item><item><title>Creator collective</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/creator-collective/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/creator-collective/</guid><description>We hear over and over that creativity is always one of the best skill to have for the future.
Forbes says &amp;ldquo;Creativity will be one of the most desirable skills in the future workplace&amp;rdquo;*
WEF puts &amp;ldquo;Creativity, originality and initiative&amp;rdquo; among the top 10 skills of 2025.*
But why do so many creatives struggle? I start with the Big Questions
&amp;ldquo;What if creators were valued as much as business people?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT is getting crazy</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/chatgpt-is-getting-crazy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/chatgpt-is-getting-crazy/</guid><description>Trying to learn what I can do with ChatGPT and found this. Seems like imagination is the only limiting factor.
{{tweet https://twitter.com/skirano/status/1635736107949195278?s=20}}
So I tried it too. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have to do the first set up prompt. All I asked was one line.
generate code for a pong like game in javascript and HTML
Take a look at the game here → Pong.html</description></item><item><title>Joy without Guilt</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/joy-without-guilt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/joy-without-guilt/</guid><description>I am very grateful, and I feel very fortunate. I just came back from a one week trip to Los Cabos Mexico.
Feeling Joy Escaping the grey weather.
Being in such a beautiful exotic surrounding with palm trees, clear blue sky, and wales playing in the deep blue of the ocean.
Meeting people, experiencing different cultures.
Nurturing body and mind with time to pause, delicious food and sweet drinks.</description></item><item><title>I am grateful</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/i-am-grateful/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/i-am-grateful/</guid><description>I am grateful.</description></item><item><title>Northern lights road trip plan</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/northern-lights-road-trip-plan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/northern-lights-road-trip-plan/</guid><description>One dream scenario that I want to make reality in the next several years is to go on a North America road trip with my wife in an electric camper truck. We can experience a few months of van truck life, but without burning gas, or worrying about finding a place to stay each night. I think with the right gear it can be a very simple yet comfortable trip. I have many places I would love to visit and experience.</description></item><item><title>A magical Wallet that steals money from everyone in the world</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/a-magical-wallet-that-steals-money-from-everyone-in-the-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/a-magical-wallet-that-steals-money-from-everyone-in-the-world/</guid><description>When I was young I wished that I had a magical wallet that had one paper bill inside.
What good is a wallet with only one bill inside? You might ask&amp;hellip; Well, it was a magical wallet. I would be able to take the bill out and use it. Then magically another one appeared inside this magical wallet. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be nice? It is like the goose that lays unlimited golden eggs, or the fountain that never dries.</description></item><item><title>Sending a message to the future</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/sending-a-message-to-the-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/sending-a-message-to-the-future/</guid><description>I just got a message from the past. &amp;ldquo;Allergy attack 2010&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a message from my past self who is living in 2010 suffering painfully from a bad seasonal allergy attack.
Finally, after struggling year after year from seasonal allergies, my past self, one day in 2010 realized he needs to do something about it. He sent a message to me today in the future in 2023.
I hope you never experience seasonal allergies, or any other allergies for that matter, it really sucks.</description></item><item><title>The Santa Paradox</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/the-santa-paradox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/the-santa-paradox/</guid><description>I was thinking about consciousness. Then I had a moment of profound realization. You know the moment you go from not knowing to knowing something. Our brain probably evolved to reward these moments since it feels so good when this happens. This must be the motivation for all the curious minds. Joy of learning I suppose.
Suddenly all the things other wise people said started to make sense like puzzle pieces falling into place.</description></item><item><title>What if you don't know what your goals and desires are?</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-you-dont-know-what-your-goals-and-desires-are/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/what-if-you-dont-know-what-your-goals-and-desires-are/</guid><description>We are constantly told that we should be true to ourselves and pursue our deepest desires, but what if you don’t know what your goals and desires are? What if you have no idea what your “life purpose” is or should be? Self-direction is impossible without self-knowledge. How can you know what you want if you don’t know who you are? — from Building a Second Brain Book
I feel like this is the story of my life!</description></item><item><title>Publish using Logseq and Hugo</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/publish-using-logseq-and-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/publish-using-logseq-and-hugo/</guid><description>Outline
Image of process
Idea, planting the seed, incubating seedlings, feeding growing, Harvesting, Sharing Intro
What is a thought? Thinking about thinking so called Metathinking is one of the most interesting questions or it could be a great way to get your brain stuck in an infinite Recursion.
Ideas grow in a Nonlinear Workflow
in a safe an private place, second brain, architecs and the gardeners Logseq the safe incubating ideas Page</description></item><item><title>GoHugo.io</title><link>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/gohugo.io/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugiselephant.com/pages/gohugo.io/</guid><description>https://gohugo.io/ Open Source static site generator</description></item></channel></rss>